# **EMILY HANNAN**

Full Stack Web Developer

emilyhannan@gmail.com 250-891-8411 GitHub.com/hannan-emily http://ehannan.herokuapp.com

#### **TECHNICAL SUMMARY**

Full Stack Web Developer of immersive applications with creative, responsive designs. I'm a proactive, team centered developer with over 5 years experience as a designer with agency, retail and media/publishing experience. A hybrid developer and designer who works well in broader multi-disciplinary teams. I develop responsive, design-forward web applications with delightful twists.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

**Languages:** JavaScript, Python, SQL, HTML 5, CSS, CSS Grid **Libraries:** React, Redux, jQuery, Materialize, Bootstrap **Design:** Web Fonts, Typefaces, Responsive Design, Photoshop

Frameworks: Express, Node.js, Django

**Databases:** PostgreSQL, Sequelize, MongoDB, Mongoose **Other:** AJAX, Axios, Git, GitHub, Heroku, RESTful API

# **PROJECTS**

**Mood Tracker** TEAM | Python, Django, AWS, Amazon AI Facial Recognition, Materialize

Chart your mood by analyzing your selfies! A responsive, object oriented design app in Python/Django, we utilized the Amazon Rekognition API, Charts.js and Materialize to generate a tracker of each user's mood, by their selfies.

**Apocalyprep** TEAM | React, Redux, MongoDB, Mongoose, NOAA API, React-Materialize

A comprehensive, real time emergency prep app. Built as a responsive, image-rich application in React with Redux. I built the MongoDB schema, Mongoose routing and front end styling including implementing React-Materialize.

PNW Overland INDIVIDUAL | Node.js, EJS, Express, PostgreSQL, JavaScript

An interactive Node.js app, serving as an exploration guide to Pacific Northwest off roading trails. Featuring interactive custom Google Map API calls, responsive imagery and embedded auto-play video. The app integrates the Google Maps API.

Chasing Carmen SanDiego INDIVIDUAL | HTM5 Canvas, JavaScript, jQuery UI

A delightfully fun HTML5 Canvas trivia based game, pitting two users against that international thief, Carmen SanDiego. I built the HTML Canvas app, designed custom graphics and UI elements for a responsive user experience.

### **EXPERIENCE**

# Web Development Immersive, General Assembly, Seattle, WA

Jan - April 2018

A 3-month, 60+ hrs/week, project-based web development accelerator. Educated in popular web technologies, database development, CRUD, RESTful routing, responsive UI design, Git and version control.

### Graphic Designer, Black Press, Saanich, BC

Oct 2017 - Jan 2018

Responsible for layout, graphics and advertising design for a twice weekly newspaper. Design for web and print for a range of Retail, E-Commerce, Outdoor Sports and Grocery clients. Managed client deliverables, working with external clients and internal stakeholders, including editorial, sales and design teams.

#### Graphic Designer, Media One, Victoria, BC

May - Oct 2017

UX/UI design, planning and strategy for a wide range of clients, including a Marine Suspensions Seating manufacturer, FinTech, Food Delivery app, Fishing Charters, and a Restaurant Management app. Produced client deliverables, working with external clients. Digital advertising graphic design, optimized for Google Adword placement.

## Co-Founder, The Little Red Backpack, Victoria, BC

May 2016 - May 2017

Founded a Social Media Consulting Company. Digital and web asset design, brand and content strategy for Retail, E-Commerce.

## Marketing Coordinator & Designer, Capital Iron, Victoria, BC

July 2015 - May 2017

Sole advertising designer for large corporate retailer. Managed and produced all design deliverables, managed external and internal clients and integrated SEO keywords in digital and print assets. Annual advertising budget over \$300,000.

### **EDUCATION**

Web Development Immersive, General Assembly, Seattle, WA	2018
Master of Fine Arts, Cranbrook Academy of Art, Bloomfield Hills, MI	2012
Bachelor of Fine Arts, University of Washington, Seattle, WA	2010